

Tehran, Iran

🛮 (+98) 939-177-4443 | 🗷 peymanffarahani@gmail.com | 🌴 peymanfarahani.herokuapp.com | 🖸 PFarahani | 🛅 peymanfarahani | 🐧 live:payman_fara

Qualification Summary.

High performing data scientist with a passion for business analytics and machine learning. With experience impacting positive organizational outcomes through machine learning and programming with Python. Confident in ability to collaborate with cross-functional teams to solve complex, high-stakes problems. Committed to continuous improvement and contributing to team success.

Education

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

Tehran Iran

B.Sc. IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2017 - Mar. 2022

- Obtained International Degree
- Passed 11 courses (32 credits) that were taught in English
- GPA of the last two years: 3.88/4.0
- · Scored A+ (19/20) in my BSc. thesis entitled "Credit Card Fraud Detection Using Supervised Learning Methods"

Skills

Industry Knowledge Machine Learning, Data Mining, Data Scraping, Business Intelligence, Business Process Analysis, Version control (Git)

Programming Python, C

Python Libraries Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Spacy, TuriCreate, Plotly, Scrapy

Software Weka, SPSS Modeler, SPSS, MS Access, SQL Server, Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, Visio, Visual Paradigm

Languages Persian, English, German

Projects _____

SELECTED PROJECTS

Credit Card Fraud Detection Using Supervised Learning Methods

Undergraduate Thesis Aug. 2021

- · Seven supervised machine learning methods were used on 2 million credit card transactions in order to find the best fraud detection model.
- The SMOTE method was used to overcome the problem of dataset imbalance.
- Robust Scaling was identified as the best method for scaling the data.
- · By evaluating the results of MCC and AUROC, Random Forest model was selected as the best model for predicting fraudulent transactions.

Spotify Music Taste Discovery

Individual Project Feb. 2021

- Extracted "Discover Weekly" playlist's data from Spotify.
- After pre-processing, a radar chart was drawn indicating the music genre tendency.

Financial Database

"MODELING AND DATABASE" COURSE PROJECT

Dec. 2020

- Designed a database in SQL server for the "Finance Department of SAIPA"
- The data used was provided by the Finance Department of SAIPA Corp.

TSE Stocks Analysis

INDIVIDUAL PROJECT Oct, 2020

- Tehran stocks market analysis done on all available stock tickers.
- The data was derived from official TSE (Tehran Stock Exchange) website by using data scraping tools
- The obtained data was stored in a database
- Using machine learning methods, tickers' behavior during future 7 days were predicted.

Vehicle Specification Clustering

SAIPA PROJECT Sep. 2020

- Using k-means algorithm with the aid of PCA analysis, a segmentation was done based on all available cars' specifications in Iran's market.
- The data used was provided by "Center of Strategic Studies of SAIPA".

SAIPA Financial Dashboard

SAIPA Project Aug. 2020

 A dashboard was created for the biggest automobile company in Iran which showed all financial information of that company between 2015 and 2020.

- The information in this dashboard includes the financial statements of SAIPA and were collected by the Finance Department.
- The results were presented to the senior management of SAIPA during a working meeting.

Note: These projects are only a selection of all completed projects. Please visit my website to see the complete information of all projects.

Work Experience_

Ara Jahan Novin Gostar-e Atlas (Snapptrip)

Tehran, Irai

COMMERCIAL DATA ANALYST INTERN

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Using Python to design and develop crawler scripts that extract data of domestic flights from websites. Finally, analyzing the information acquired to adjust the flight pricing guidelines.
- Using Excel to analyze hotel sales data to determine the firm's market share of online reservations
- · Uncovering areas for improvement and developing and implementing solutions using machine learning and data analysis tools.

SAIPA Corp. Tehran, Ira

BUSINESS PROCESS ANALYST Dec. 2020 - Apr. 2021

- Design and correction of system processes using BPMN 2.0 tools through Visual Paradigm software.
- Correcting and updating regulations and executive methods of quality control department.
- · Prepare performance reports and management dashboards for the systems engineering department of SAIPA

SAIPA Corp.

Tehran, Iran

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Data analysis
- · Data mining in order to gain organizational insight
- · Creating dashboards using Microsoft Power Bl.

Professional Development

ONLINE COURSES

Aug. 2022 **Deep Learning Specialization**, DeepLearning.Al

Oct. 2021 NLP - Natural Language Processing with Python, Udemy

Oct. 2020 Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp, Udemy

Aug. 2020 IBM SPSS Modeler Essentials, Udemy

July 2020 Microsoft Access 2016 Master Class: Beginner to Advanced, Udemy

July 2020 Tableau 10 Advanced Training: Master Tableau in Data Science, Udemy

June 2020 Tableau 10 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training For Data Science!, Udemy

May. 2020 The Complete Python 3 Course: Beginner to Advanced!, Udemy

Mar. 2020 Microsoft Power BI - A Complete Introduction, Udemy

CERTIFICATES

Dec. 2019 Python Programming with Data Science Approach, Khaje Nasir Toosi University of Technology

July 2018 Basic Python Programming, Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic)

Honors & Awards

2019-2020 Top 5% students for two consecutive semesters, Department of Industrial Engineering

June 2019 Golden Certificate of Achievement, International Language Center of Amirkabir University of Technology

Dec. 2018 Certificate of Appreciation, CEIT 30th anniversary

Membership & Activities

Tehran, Irar

Oct. 2020 - Oct. 2021

Core Member & Director of Finance

- Modified the financial sector and used new tools such as Excel and Power BI to report financial activities.
- In cooperation with the sponsorship department, a number of sponsors in the industry were attracted to support the association's programs.
- Designed advertising packages.
- · Created and updated the statute of Scientific Association of Industrial Engineering with the cooperation of other core members.

"MASAAF" Student-Scientific Journal (Amirkabir University of Technology)

Tehran, Iran

MEMBER OF EDITORIAL BOARD

Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2020

· Collecting and writing the latest information related to various fields of industrial engineering and publishing it in the journal.

"Tanin" Music Band Tehran, Iran

SANTOOR PLAYER AND BAND LEADER

Sep. 2017 - Oct. 2021

- Performed in official university ceremonies
- Performed in faculty ceremonies and celebrations

References.

Dr. Reyhane Gamasaee

Assistant Professor

Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic) gamasaee@aut.ac.ir

Dr. Ali Safari

Assistant Professor; Mehralborz University (MAU)
Systems Engineering General Manager; SAIPA Corp.
alisafari@ut.ac.ir
safari@saipacorp.com

Dr. Vahid Kayvanfar

Lecturer of Industrial Engineering Sharif University of Technology kayvanfar@sharif.edu